In a private network architecture.
The end-device, the gateways and the servers belong to us. In a public network architecture,
we have only the device and we use the operators, gateway and operators service.
But we saw that one major drawback of a public network is that you can't place the gateway wherever you
want.
So in the case of none of these situations is suitable.
There is an alternate solution between public and private network.
In that case, we'll use our own gateways, but we'll use the service of a LoRaWAN provider for the service.
It's called a hybrid network.
That solution allows us to manage the network coverage, but for the server will still rely on the LoRaWAN
provider.
So we don't have to care about the complexity of that part.
At the beginning of this lecture.
That is the type of network that we've used. For the tests and demonstrations,
we've indeed use our own end-device and gateway. And we registered them on a network server provider called
TTN.
But I've already said that. Later in this course we'll also set up our own network server in order to
build a complete private network.
Okay.
Now, there is one last type of architecture that I want to explain, and I will do it in the next video.